Sorry everyone, my computer did a little
flip. I hope we don't have a repeat of
what happened last week during the end
of life. Uh admitting everybody from the
lobby. Um and so here we go. As usual,
good morning everyone. Uh this meeting
is being recorded and so uh as usual, we
want to ensure that we are able to post
it to the website publicly. So, please
remember to keep your language to
appropriate language for a public
meeting. Um, and this is the medical
psilocybin advisory board with Ian Dunn
as the chair. I am the Dominic Zerlo. I
am the director for the New Mexico
Department of Health Center on medical
cannabis and psilocybin. And with that,
I turn the meeting over to you, Ian, as
the chair.
>> Uh, good morning everyone. My name is
Ian Dunn. As the chair of the medical
psilocybin advisory board, I call this
meeting to order at 9:02 a.m. uh
mountain daylight time. I want to
welcome my fellow board members, the
department of health staff, and the
members of the public who are joining us
today. Um we have some ground to cover
this meeting as we work for toward
finalizing our um pragmatic rules. So,
thank you all for your time and
dedication. Uh we will begin with roll
call and introductions. I will turn over
to Dominic Zerlo and the department to
take role for the board members and
introduce the program staff present
today.
>> Thank you Ian. Um and I'll just go ahead
and go down the list. Um we have uh uh
Brenda Burgard.
>> Morning every
morning every morning. Good morning
everyone. I'm Brenda Burgard. I'm uh the
chair for training and education and I
want to thank you all for coming today.
Uh let's uh roll up our sleeves today
and really take a look at uh what we
have on the agenda today and um have
some conversation about it. Thank you
all for being here today.
>> Thank you, Brenda. Uh next we have Chris
Pascus. Chris,
>> good morning everyone. Chris Dusky here.
I think you all know who I am by now.
Happy to be here. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Chris. Um, and Dan Jennings.
Good morning.
>> Hey, good morning. Dan Jennings, uh,
vice chair of the board and the chair of
the research and continuous improvement
committee. Good morning.
>> Thank you, Dan. Um, Desba, good morning.
>> Yeah. Hey, I'm Desba. I chair the
equity, access, and cultural
considerations committee. Good morning.
>> Thank you, Desma. Uh Ian Dunn. Good
morning.
>> Good morning, everyone. My name is Ian
Dunn. I am chair of the medical
psilocybin advisory board as well as the
patient qualification and safety
committee and the dosage administration
and clinical practice committee. Happy
to be here.
>> Good morning, Ian. Thank you. And uh
Kenan Ryan.
Good morning all. Uh Kim Ryan, I'm the
acting chief medical officer for New
Mexico Medicaid. Um also pharmacist by
training, our director of pharmacy. I am
the voting designign for the board
member Lana Dancis who is our acting
Medicaid director. So um she wishes she
could be here more often, but as you can
imagine, it's a
tumultuous time in Medicaid these days.
>> Thank you, Kenan. And good morning uh
Larry Leman. Good morning.
>> Yeah. Hi everybody. Larry Leman, board
member, chair of the end of life
committee, um psychedelic researcher and
therapist at UNM.
Good to see everybody.
>> Okay, I believe those are all the board
members. Did I miss anybody?
Nope, that that is everybody. All seven.
Um, and so from the department side, um,
as I mentioned earlier, I'm Dominic
Zerlo. I'm the, uh, the director for the
New Mexico Department of Health, Center
for Medical Cannabis and Psilocybin. And
joining us from the department in the
program side, we also have um, uh, Jorge
Gonzalez who is our medical psilocybin
program manager. We have Brenda Martinez
who is our deputy director for the
center. We have Raymond Gyos who is an
analyst with our program. Johnny Musher
without whom we would not have these
invites for the program uh and uh is our
management analyst. We have Rose Nava
who is our um health education program
manager. um Cyrus Routtman who is our
environmental scientist uh Vicente Royal
who is an intern with the program and
Dr. Robert Truckner who is um uh our
medical director for the program. Um we
do also as we are continuing with um
working on the program and looking at
implementation we have some of our other
program staff who are joining to see
because they're also going to be doing
things for example taking phone calls
from potential patients providers and
providing some information. So with
that, we also have Danza Aragon who is
one of our uh one of our team on our
patient services side and so to be able
to be here and hear a little bit of
what's happening. So thank you everybody
and I'll turn it back over to you Ian.
>> Thank you. Um so to review the agenda of
what we are going over today, um we are
going to recap what we did cover in the
last meeting that we updated. Um one of
our three core requirements that we
needed to solve was the implementation
deadline. We pushed it back to December
of 2027. Um what we still needed to vote
on was the a to actually defer the
educational curriculum to the training
and education committee. Um the
in-person medical exam requirement and
then the controlled substance number
which uh Dominic had deferred to the
uh had rechecked in with the secretary
of health and reassessed and he he may
have updates on that. we will hear what
he heard back. Um and then other
business as and ending with the public
comment any additions, changes to the
agenda.
Cool. So without objection, we will go
ahead and move forward. So, as our recap
on the last meeting, kind of went over
that briefly, but we um had moved
forward to push that reciprocal
practical hour requirement to December
2027. Um, we will now go ahead and if
there is not objection, we can move to a
vote on to defer the training and
education practicum and dactic hours to
the training and education committee for
them to solve um to reassess and reccome
together and have time to come up with
those updated standards.
Are there any objections to holding the
vote?
Cool. All right. So, we'll go ahead and
move to uh defer those to the training
and education committee. Uh if you are
in favor of moving those practicum and
dactic hours back to the training and
education committee, please raise your
hand at this time.
Cool. I see seven hands. Um,
perfect. You can lower your hands at
this time.
While I know there is not Casper the
ghost in the room with us, I do have to
give option. If anyone would object to
this, please raise your hand at this
time.
No, Casper. Uh, the motion is adopted.
We will send that back to the training
and education committee. Um, and then we
will work on the updates from the
department. So, what did you hear back,
Dominic?
Oh, you're muted.
>> Thank you so much, Ian. Uh, that that's
what happens when you go to try to copy
and paste some items um into the chat.
So, um, the first thing I wanted to do
because I know this was one of the
questions that had come up, uh,
specifically was with regard to the
in-person portion. Um, and so I'm
putting that that language what we have
adjusted into the chat. Um and
essentially just to kind of go over over
this is that um there would be um the
certifying clinician would still need to
conduct an in-person exam of the patient
within the previous six months. So not
necessarily at that appointment where
they are doing that. They could do that
final appointment as teleaalth if they
have seen that patient in person in the
previous six months. In addition to that
they could also do teaalth or telea
medicine if they have done a review of
the medical records pertaining to the
diagnosis for the qualifying condition
from a clinician who has uh examined the
individual in person within the previous
six months. or if that is burdensome,
they can do the same thing but make sure
that they have a formal consult with the
clinician who has conducted an in-person
exam in the previous six months. So this
allows that the the safety aspect is
there that the patient has had an
examination in the last six months but
it doesn't necessarily need to be the
certifying clinician who has performed
that exam but they are consulting with
them whether through records or through
that formal consult process and uh and
so at that point I' I'd just like to say
what people think about that um and that
would help especially I think in rural
areas situations that Larry had brought
up regarding end of life, all of those
kinds of situations.
Oh, and I should as a reminder just uh
the board um uh protocols are that this
portion is discussion for the board at
this time, not public comment. Public
comment will be at the end. So, uh with
that in mind, Ian, go ahead.
>> Yeah, I was just curious. So, there are
several professionals that can perform
an assessment, obviously a physician.
Um, would a an RN who typically performs
headtotoe assessments be able to provide
that assessment material or would it
have to be another um like MDNP,
BO,
that kind of thing?
>> Great question, Ian. And it's actually
why we have the language clinician um
which actually fits within the statutory
language on it. Um and so that would
cover for example those particular uh
lensures.
Chris, go ahead, Chris.
>> So, how broad are we trying to make
certifying clinician? Can you
break it down um
a little bit for me? So, I I'm
understanding
who would be able to conduct this.
>> Sure. So the certifying clinician at
least on the with the definition that we
have currently is an individual who it
is within their scope of practice or
scope of work to be able to diagnose and
who has a CS number.
And so that's what that would limit for
that certifying clinician. But again
remember the consult with the other
clinician or the medical records may be
from someone else with a different
lensure.
So,
we're just adding another
layer to this or we're I don't I don't
see how this helps. Now we're adding
other options for the certifying
clinician to be able to ensure that
there has been a medical exam and but
not necessarily to do that part in
person themselves that they could do
that through tele medicine
as long as they have either the patient
records or do the consult with someone
who has performed that exam.
So, if I'm understanding this right,
we're going to have we're still going to
have the certifying clinicians under
this this proposal. We'll still have the
certifying clinicians
at pretty much with the same rule they
had in the last model, but now they'll
just be able to consult with your
primary care or
>> an RN who's done a evaluation on you.
>> That's correct.
How will the liability work with this?
Because this still puts a certifying
clinician in the chain of liability
which confuses
where that liability lies in this
process.
And it
how does it
I still don't think this helps encourage
doc anybody to become a certifying
clinician when all of the risk
mitigation comes from you know the the
preparation
and administration
practices and the integration from the
facilitator and the practitioner. So
I don't really think this helps in any
way.
So uh to answer the question, it doesn't
change the liability. Um
any individual who is performing or
engaged with regard to a controlled one
substance does have to assume that
liability. But as we've sort of talked
about before, we've had that situation
for almost two decades with cannabis and
that has not been an issue or a problem.
>> But you don't do cannabis with somebody
who's performing all the risk mitigation
for that practice. So like
>> well
at the same point the clinical or the
certifying clinician is simply
certifying that the individual has been
medically clear. They are not actually
conducting any of the administration or
administration sessions. So that
liability still would reside where it
has throughout the entire process with
those individuals
>> with you're saying all the liability
lies with the
with the facilitator and the
practitioner. No, I'm saying that it
hasn't changed that
having this simply ensures that the
patient has had an exam to ensure that
they medically are able to go through
the treatment.
That's all that it does.
Um, Ryan, you're next.
>> Thank you. I'm sorry. My apologies. No
problem.
>> It throws me off every time when I see
the last name, first name. So, my
apologies, Keenan.
>> I get it. It's It's the way the state
reports our email, you know, our our
Zoom pieces, as you know. Um, a lot of
my initial questions were actually
answered by the questions Chris asked.
So, thank you for that. The the initial
certifying physician
is providing that they're one medically
cleared and two have diagnosed
appropriate for this. Is that correct?
>> That's correct.
>> Okay. So, it should be those two pieces
that they are healthy enough
uh to investigate this. Obviously the
final determination should be made by
the facilitator and the member patient
together informed decision-m to to make
that on them but that they're healthy
enough potentially do this medical risk
are probably pretty minimal but say if
they have uncontrolled hypertension etc
should not be looking at it and then
um
that they have one of the approved
diagnoses as we said for three
uh that's helpful thank you
>> thank you Ken
Uh Ian, you were next.
>> Yeah. So just to clarify because I think
it kind of addresses Chris's point. Um
so typically in medical tors we have a
duty and a breach. So in this case the
duty of the um
uh certifying clinician is to evaluate
their health records and their current
physiological state. Um, so a breach
could only happen if they failed those
duties. Therefore, if like the
facilitator, the risk mitigator down the
line has a duty and they breach it, then
that would be on them. It wouldn't be on
the the
certifying clinician. Am I understanding
that correct?
>> That is my understanding as well.
>> Uh, Larry.
>> Yeah. Hi. Um, two two comments. One on
the um on the risk part of it. Um, what
Ian says is sort of true, but it doesn't
actually usually help in a lawsuit. They
bring anybody in, including the person
who is cleaning the hospital room. So,
it doesn't usually help in that way. I I
don't know if any um if there is
actually a way to actually be clear in
the stipulation actually that even says
the this individual is not responsible.
I wonder if there's some way we can be
more protective of that of that
clinician there. That's really a
question for any of our lawyer friends
that might be on the call. Um the other
question is, you know, it's come up
several times that some of the
requirements for the CS number um is has
to do with psilocybin being a a schedule
one substance. Um, however, is although
it's not a slam dunk, I think almost
almost everyone thinks that by the
middle of 2027, if not sooner, it will
no longer be a schedule one. It'll be a
schedule three. And I just wanted to,
you know, um, get an idea if that would
allow for a different approach um, when
you're in schedule three than than when
you're in schedule one. I think that's a
question for you, Dom, actually.
Yeah, if that were to happen, that could
definitely be re-evaluated.
>> And let me just then share from my my
own knowledge from being a researcher on
some of the phase three. I mean, the
although [clears throat] it's not a slam
dunk and we thought this was true with
MDMA, that is the overwhelming feeling
that that's likely to happen. And so it
may be important for us to be just
considering that as we move forward.
Thank you.
>> Thank you, Larry.
Chris,
>> I'm curious. So my understanding of
psilocybin is that it is incredibly safe
and I think that some of the cardio
uh vascular issues that we're concerned
or are concerned
um and that are commonly brought up are
vastly overblown. I'm wondering uh Dr.
Dr. Leman, if you can speak to the
safety of psilocybin and where the real
physical risks lie.
>> Dr. Leman, would you like to respond?
>> Sure. Um, thank you, Chris. Um,
it's not a one minute answer, but unfort
but I'm going to try to give it a, you
know, a so much shorter answer. Um,
yeah, I think it's true. psilocybin on
the risk of substances is very low.
There's been charts that there's almost
no risk for for instance for uh you know
for addiction. Um the issues come up
with people that have coorbidities. Um
you know if you have someone who already
has you know some cardiovascular issues
and you raise their blood pressure then
they could [clears throat] find
themselves having ana or or even a
stroke. So I think there's in those
situations which should be reasonably
easy to screen for. Um so I think that'd
be part of it. I think that there are
other risks that have to do with with
mental health and with challenging um
you know with challenging experiences.
Um um that's probably the you know the
greater situation. I mean I mean one one
way and and and unfortunately I'll be
honest I don't think all these are
getting recorded in the literature
because I keep hearing about cases but
the concerns that happen are people
being transported to the emergency room
for um challenging experiences which
part of the risk there actually becomes
iatrogenic at the point when that
happens they're they're not unlikely to
get an antiscychotic or even admitted to
a mental health hospital. So in some of
those the medical system you know
creates those um you know those risks.
There are I am aware of also you know
and you know we used to say that there
are no cases of um serotonin syndrome.
There seems to be one you know that's um
that I've heard about anecdotally that
that occur. So those those are rare. But
I I say Chris in general what I I would
support what you're saying this is a
very safe substance. We're not We have,
you know, tens of like tens of thousands
of people now in Oregon that have used
it in in just a handful of issues. I
would say it is a very safe substance.
Chris, did I answer that?
Yeah, I think so. Um, and
in your I guess I'm still struggling
with the necessity of having somebody
with a controlled
um, substance license number
having to be involved in in the
screening and medical safety of such a
safe substance.
>> Yeah. Um, I would, um, well, okay, I'll
go on a little bit of a limb. So, um, I
would say that, um, that would not be
necessary for for every everyone. It
probably wouldn't be necessary for
someone with just major major
depression. Um, I I think it probably
would be um, essential for somebody who
had opioid use disorder. And so I think
that that in the system if I was
designing a system for scratch I would
go back to doing it based on indications
and say these indications need that. Um
so that's what I would do. So this is
not exactly how I would design it. And I
I think to be realistic you say I mean
we're we're being required to do this by
the um you know by the executive
division. And so I I think that's why
we're we're we're here. And even though
some of us don't agree with it, I think
it's going to be hard to change that. I
I do think though, this is why I brought
up the schedule scheduling. I think that
that may be a major way that we can
revise things in in the coming year,
but no, I would not require it for
everybody, Chris.
And and just to be clear, so I will go
back for a moment to the part about the
controlled substance number is at this
point, you know, I did bring the
concerns that were expressed previously
back to the secretary. We had a
discussion about it. Um we have talked
with the attorneys as well for for
department of health and really this
being a medical program that is going to
be a requirement that the department is
putting forward. And so just to let
everybody know um I it is a medical
program does need to go through that the
part Larry just talked about with regard
to doing it for different uh
considerations. We understand that we
can't actually do that for one condition
but not for another with within a
regulatory framework. It has to be done
across the board um for that. And um and
so with that in mind because there are
circumstances especially with some of
the comorbidity issues where people do
need to have that medical clearance do
need to have that that is something that
is going to be proposed in the rules for
the department. So just to clarify that
that is going to be an aspect I did
bring it back as I mentioned to the
secretary and that is however going to
be a part of it. So within that
framework, we need to look at this
language within that and to see is this
going to allow for that additional
options especially with regard to rural
areas and with other areas uh such as
end of life and other things to be able
to provide that access. So with that
Keenan
>> can I just ask one question? uh Dominic
or members from the DU who have this
historic knowledge. Uh is this the same
requirement that was required for
medical marijuana when we started or
medical cannabis when that program was
started? Do you know?
>> Uh yes, it is. It has always been
required to for the certifying
clinicians to have a CS number.
>> Got it. Perfect. Okay, that's that's
good to know. I think that helps
establish that we're really following
uh existing protocol. If it wasn't in
there, I would make a strong argument
for it to not be here, but as a
standard, I'm okay with that. And I do
think it's important to separate out
clinical risk and the legal risk. Um,
and I think we keep using risk and they
kind of get mixed together. I think the
clinical risk, um, as Dr. Leman said is
the these are safe meds and safer than a
lot of
other agents we give that aren't even
controlled substance. There's plenty of
non-controlled but prescription
medications that are way more toxic I
would say than these. That said, I
wouldn't recommend someone um who
recently had a heart attack
uh to be ready for this until they're
cleared by a cardiologist, right? Like I
think that's what we want this
certifying physician uh piece to say is
that oh yeah, you're
the risk is short-term while you're on
this guided experience. You could have
some high blood pressure that could
cause an urgency or emergency depending
on the the state of your cardiovascular
system and we just want to make sure
that you're healthy enough to go through
that uh specific piece at that time. So,
I hope that kind of helps clarify what
what I was trying to um
explain earlier. And if I'm speaking out
um on something that's a little
different than you see, Dr. Leman, or
anybody else, please please inform me.
>> Okay. Thank you, Kenan. Um I would like
to defer to Dr. Trekner uh from the
department. Dr. Truckner,
>> thank you. Thank you, Keen. And I I
think you answered my question, Chris.
The medicine may be safe, right? It's
not a toxic medication, but the worry is
the safety, the health status of the
people who are taking the medication,
right? We are going to have in general a
much sicker population if you want to
use that. They're going to have other
coorbidities. And as Ken's example, if
you had a recent heart attack, do you
want to do that? If you have diabetes,
do we need to make sure that's clear? So
the medication may be safe. We are going
to have a different patient population
in the state and I generally expect that
we're going to they're going to have
higher illness burdens, so to speak. So
that's why this I believe this is
necessary. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Um, and uh, next we have
Despa. Despa,
>> hi. Thank you, uh, Kenan and Dr. uh,
Truckner for those explanations as well
as Larry. Um, to Larry's point, um, you
know, it sounds like to assess actually
three different kinds of risks. One, the
risk of the substance itself. Two, the
legal risk as Kenan pointed out. And
then three, as uh, Dr. Truckner also
kind of is associated with the legal
risk is the health risk of the person um
aside from the sub like the substance
itself right so one is um dependent on
the other um but to that point and what
um Larry had talked about earlier you
know as long as the substance is you
know and then maybe this is completely
over overdone done. But you know, as
long as the substance is remains a
control uh you know, a class one, right,
schedule one, um this is how these are
going to be conducted, which then
alleviates this idea, right? I think
Larry, to your point, that in the future
as a as a schedule 3, then that kind of
eliminates itself kind of like a BCC
[laughter]
in some ways of of this idea of the
substance. I don't know if that makes
more sense. And I don't know if that's
even necessary, but I think that's what
I hear Larry was kind of getting at um
as far as you know, it's this is way
now, but allowing us to be able to as
it's moving forward, then this is when
when uh it will be re-evaluated.
>> Thank you. Uh Dan Jennings,
>> I appreciate it. Um, and the question I
was going to ask, and I just noticed
that Kenan put in the chat that he's
away, but um, so my question of this is
this would be an additional expense for
a patient to go through because they've
already seeing their primary physician,
they've already got a diagnosis. Um,
they've already been, you know, they're
through their medical evaluations there.
So, this would be somebody else. So, the
question I was, is this like an ENM
visit? Uh, is this something that can be
covered under basic insurance evaluation
and management? this basic insurance,
Medicaid possibility that the um the
diagnosing the clinician that we're
talking about here could be billable
back to insurance. Like I said, I just
don't want to I mean, it's going to be
an additional expense. So, I just wanted
to check on that.
>> Sure. Thank you, Dan. And I'm going to
defer to Dr. Truckner since he's more of
an expert on that aspect than I am.
>> Yeah. Hi, Dan. Yeah, that should be
available. that really should be
available on evaluation management card.
>> I appreciate it. Thank you
>> Chris.
>> Um I guess I just want to challenge this
notion that our population is going to
be so much more vulnerable than the
populations in Colorado and Oregon. I've
talked to too many people working in
both of those states that are working
with very sick people. they are able to
do these evaluations at a much lower
level um and effectively and work
through consultation with people's
people's existing care teams. Um you
know you can buy a ticket to Burning Man
for the same price that you can go get
treatment in Oregon or Colorado. So, I'm
just I'm really struggling with um that
thought process that our our population
is so much sicker than uh and more
vulnerable than the people that are
doing this safely and effectively in
Colorado and Oregon.
>> Thank you, Larry.
>> Oh, Larry, you're still on mute.
>> Thanks. Just respond. That was what I
was thinking about. Um um here here
here's my global thoughts on this here.
I mean I think I've already given my
thoughts on how I would design a system
if I was given ultimate power. Clearly I
don't none of us have ultimate power and
we're kind of dealing with the with the
requirements of the um you know of the
legislative and the governor and the
fact that it is a medical bill. Um I see
that there a couple of things that may
happen in the future. we may get
rescheduled into schedule 3. I think
that's extremely likely. And so a
question I would have maybe for Dom is
like, you know, what is the actual, you
know, process then for us to change the
processes if that happened. The other
issue that also there's concerns are is
that that the process that we're
developing will be a big bottleneck and
and I don't know. I mean, I we have we
have opinions either way. I I think it
might be I don't know again if it was
what would be the process for us to
change the certifying clinician because
I think if we can appreciate that we
have a way of changing that and that
we're likely to have a schedule three
drug maybe we can move forward with you
know apparently all we're really going
to be allowed to do is to is to do this
approach and maybe we can have unity on
that even if we don't all agree with the
approach.
>> Thank you Larry. It would be a similar
process as far as uh with doing rule
changes where what we essentially would
do is go through the publication of the
proposed rule, have the public hearing
and then uh and then make those changes
uh based upon the feedback and public
comment from um you know from that
public hearing.
Did you have something else? Thank you,
Don.
Great.
>> No, I think that answered both
questions.
>> And again, I'd like to defer to Dr.
Trekner.
>> Larry, help me out here. Is it I mean,
I'm I've had a DEA license forever and
I've just never really paid attention to
what it allows and doesn't allow. Isn't
a schedule three drug still that require
a DEA license?
Do you know? I'm I'm just not sure.
It's a It requires a different kind of
Right now the like I have a there's
probably like three people in the state
that have a schedule one license and I
think right now we're all at at UNM. So
they're strictly they're very strictly
regulated. Partially it's based on a
fallacy. It's based on the idea that the
schedule one drugs have no benefit and
and are are abusable and this one is
neither which is true about this one. So
I think it will it will get moved out of
there. Yeah, that that was really a
question that I that I had as far as as
far as how that would change in the you
know change in the state. Um, [snorts] I
I think it it changes somewhat about how
the way view different uh different
drugs, but yes, you still need a DEA
license, but you wouldn't need a
schedule one DEA license.
>> Thank you. Yeah. So I I guess my main
point is even if we reschedu it for most
of us quote normal physicians who don't
who who don't have the special license
um I will still I I for a schedule three
drug for me to prescribe it I'll still
need a DEA therefore a CS license in the
state of Mexico.
>> Correct.
>> Yeah, that would be true. But but I
think this is like this isn't really a
prescription. This is like a form that
we're completing. So I think that you
know that may be the difference here. I
totally agree with you. um you probably
wouldn't change that part of it. Um we
also even don't even know exactly how
for psilocybin how it's going to be
managed. It's unlikely to be a
prescription that you bring to a
pharmacy. It's likely going to go
through like a rem process
>> Chris.
Okay. So, are we requiring uh
one of those three people with a
schedule one DEA license to do this?
>> No.
>> So,
but this is like completely
contradictory. We're saying you need a
DEA license to prescribe
because it's a schedule one substance,
but we're not requiring the the people
with a schedule one substance to to do
this.
>> No, that Larry, were you going to say
something?
>> Yeah, I mean Chris, it's a great
question. There there's a lot of
contraindication to this. we're
basically dealing with a state program
that is um is sanctioning the use of
something that's a federal substance
based on state law. So that's why
there's seem to be those contra
contradictions there. Um um
I I think there's awareness that is
although it's extremely unlikely um you
know it's always possible if you had
some change of hearted administration
that they could come down in any of the
three states. I think that's extremely
unlikely to happen. But I think that's
that's a contradiction. The schedule one
is based on a federal law that we can't
change. The um but if it's changed into
schedule three in general, people start
viewing as a different drug. So the
question would be more if it was moved
into schedule three, would that change
some of the political realities about a
medical bill and being able to establish
another process? There's another part
that was in my question really which was
um if it turns out that that and we
probably will know within six or nine
months whether this is a big limitation
how hard is it to change it in other
words if we if this moved ahead in
January 27 and you know 6 or nine months
later it was it was found to be a big
obstacle which I I think is a reasonable
concern but I don't think we know
that'll happen. How hard would it be to
change that?
Part of this I'm putting in the context
of that I'm very much hoping that
there's going to be a fix it bill
because what's going to be presented in
the training committee this afternoon is
impossible to do um adequate training
without um having the ability for people
to use psilocybin in the training. And I
think one of the hopes of that fix it
bill is that it'll include major
depressive disorder which deals with
another major limit. I mean, if I think
that was our intention to do that,
having been part of the bill formation
and if that gets changed, it'll probably
triple the number of people who are
eligible based on the criteria. It'll
make training easier. It'll also mean
that there are more people that are
being treated that are not quite as
sick. So, I think I think a lot may be
changed. And personally, I suspect that
we're going to be revisiting things, you
know, after that that um after that bill
revision. Just my own prediction.
>> Didn't the didn't the bill didn't
statute remove this substance from the
schedule one list?
I don't remember it reclassifying it.
>> So it it only does so for the purposes
of treatment within the program. But
part of what this is is that with it
still being schedule one there we still
have to have an those uh assurities
because it is a medication and so with
that that is why uh it actually has the
CS number because while it is not a
prescription um it is essentially
treated as such going through this
process even though it is not a a
prescription on either a federal or a
state level and that's a part of the
reason Why having that requirement
actually helps to bolster that aspect
that it is similar although it is not a
prescription that the certification is
similar but not a prescription
and so uh Dr. sharpener.
>> Now, Chris, I think to to try to answer
your question, um, first, no, you're not
going to let's go back a couple steps.
The reason we develop three pathways
for a patient to be able to enter the
program is because we heard your
comments saying, hey, you know, getting
to see quote a certifying physician may
be a hardship for a lot of people. So,
by giving three three different options,
you can live in some small town in New
Mexico and if I'm a certifying
clinician, I can talk to your doc and
say, "Hey, tell me about patient X, show
me their medical records. Okay, that
seems reasonable." So, this was our our
attempt, and I think it's completely
reasonable to open up the ability for
patients who don't have access
immediately close to a certifying
clinician.
um it gives three three different
options. Now to go back to answer your
question about controlled substances I
think Chris in the world of medicine a
large number of physicians a large
number of nurse practitioners and a few
others all have all can qualify for a
DEA license. So there's actually a
fairly large pool of health care
providers who have or qualified for a
DEA license. So that's not really a
barrier for this at all. I I hope that
helps answer your question.
>> Chris, go ahead.
Can we Okay. I feel like this got
dodged. Can did the statute remove
psilocybin from schedule one substance
list in New Mexico?
>> So, as I said, Chris, it removed it for
purposes of the program, but it did not
completely remove it from schedule one.
But again, the the issue is is that it's
still treated as a prescription.
prescriptions are actually not written
for schedule one with as Larry said
except for very rare circumstances. Um
it's really on the schedule three level
uh uh on that aspect. And so but what we
have seen with medications such as
cannabis that are illicit on the federal
level but legal on the state level, the
certification from the provider is
treated similarly to a prescription. And
so that's why it we're doing the same
sort of situation here because then that
helps to create that same pathway that
we would with any other medication
and because the bill is showing this and
treating this as a medication and a
medical program. That's why that's a
part of why that aspect is there so that
it follows that same already established
pathway.
>> But my point is we're we're setting up
this program.
So, and it was descheduled for this
program. It wasn't rescheduled.
>> It was the same situation that we
experienced with cannabis. And so,
that's part of why we're following that
same pathway.
Yes, Bob.
>> Um,
so I think, and I probably have this
wrong myself, but what it sounds like is
[clears throat]
I guess I'm just trying to understand
when I'm hearing the the the medication,
the prescriptions, right? So there's a
difference between why an RN and a nurse
practitioner can prescribe medications,
right? So there are certain scopes I
guess of who can actually prescribe a
medication. Nurse practitioners can, RNs
can't, they can only administer. So
that's like one layer. The next layer is
like the classification of the substance
is federal level, right? Where it's a
schedule one. And as I'm hearing it in
New Mexico, it's because there's like an
addendum to that for the purposes of
medical use and treatment within the
state because the state then has decided
for itself that we are going to be
moving this forward regardless of what
the federal is doing, you know, kind of
sort of like the right hand leftand kind
of situation. Um, so we're able to then,
you know, have our own rules and
regulations and saying that we're going
to use this substance for this medical
purpose. So there's kind of like two, I
don't want to say conflicting, but two
different pieces and layers. One where
it's a medication, one where it's a
schedule one classification. But with
the addendum, then it kind of moves it
into this like middle ground gray area.
Am I kind of understanding it a little
bit as like the two different or three
different sides?
>> Yes. Overall, yes.
>> And Ian,
would
the whole controlled substance part
seems to
cause issues? Would it make it better if
we just did the dangerous um drugs
license, which is to prescribe
everything other than controlled blood
pressure, medication, antibiotics,
um anything that has to be done under
the license? Like someone has to
supervise and care for your health,
would that be better for anyone?
Chris,
>> could you elaborate on that? And who
holds these licenses and how many are
there? And and I I guess I also would
like to know how many people with DEA
licenses are actually in New Mexico. Do
we have those statistics?
I'll defer to Dr. Truckner.
>> Yeah, Ken may have a better answer
because he's got all that data, but
Chris, there are uh most medical
practitioners
can qualify for a DEA license a
controlled substance number. So that
number really shouldn't be a bottleneck.
>> And uh Larry, you have your hand and
then we'll go to Kenan.
>> Yeah, thanks. Yeah. Um this is some
clarification for myself and and and if
I need clarification, I have all these
licenses. It's kind of interesting. So
um the control substance that we're
requiring, is it the state controlled
substance license or is it a DEA
license? I have I have like a I have a
general DEA license. I have a schedule
one DEA and I have a state controlled
substance. But there are people that
have the state controlled substance that
don't have any DEA license. And I'm just
trying to clarify what which license you
need to have for the certifying um
clinician form.
>> Thank you, Larry. Uh it's the state
controlled license, controlled substance
license.
>> Is that okay? And so so and and Denali I
guess I'd ask Denali she's mentioning um
um uh different different variations
different licenses um and mentioning uh
GLPs and different ones are not
scheduled and prescribing. So my
understanding again I may be ignorant
here is that I need that controlled
substance license from the state to
prescribe anything but maybe that's
incorrect.
Yeah, we'll go to Keenan and then to Dr.
Truckman.
>> Yeah. So, if we're in the state of New
Mexico, you don't need a controlled
substance license or DEA agent DEA
license to prescribe non-controlled
medications. Um, it's determined by the
scope of your whatever professional
licensing board. Um, for example, I had
a pharmacist clinician license. I still
have it. I just don't have an active
protocol since I moved to the state.
where I could basically prescribe any
antibiotic I wanted and uh medications
uh related to the treatment of
infectious uh disease processes but did
not hold a controlled substance license
and therefore didn't prescribe any of
those agents. So that's the distinction.
I would say that making it a controlled
substance license in the state is the
right if you're if the requirement is
that you have to have one of those
definitely at the state level and not
requiring a federal one because I think
that requires
there's more jeopardy there if you're
going to be using something that's still
a schedule one on the federal system.
Um, and making that our lensure
mechanism for it. So, um, just to add
those pieces, um, as uh, Dr. Trucker
said, the the amount of people that were
like me that had prescribing but not
controlled substances is pretty small.
Okay. Uh, Dr. contractor.
>> Yeah, Larry, I'm like you. I've had a
bunch of licenses, not the schedule one,
but I've worked in 10 states and I've
never had to have a state controlled
substance license before. So, to be
honest, I maybe Kenan has this answer. I
don't know why I need a state controlled
substance license and how it differs
from my federal license. [snorts] I
don't know. Keenan, do you have any
insight into that?
um because the state regulates
controlled uh substances on their own
schedule different that that they
require that and that's a requirement of
the state um some joint authority there.
Um what the rationale for that was I'm
not exactly sure I'm not sure if that's
specifically to allow us to diverge
um from the federal DEA schedule. And so
I I I would be guessing to be honest. I
just know like you that it's required.
And I actually reached out to the
pharmacy board and asked that question.
I and I haven't heard back from an
inspector yet. So
>> Larry,
>> yeah, I mean just just to address part
of what Denali is bringing up, which I
um can we specify that um that you do
not need a DA license, that you just
need the state controlled substance
license? that's not both of these. I
mean, would that maybe that's already
clear to some people. Obviously, it's
not clear to me. And would that would
that increase the number of providers
and be acceptable to everybody?
>> Yeah, there is not a provision to uh
that you must have a DEA license within
this proposed set of regulations.
So, we don't need to specify it
separately otherwise.
Desp it it looks like Denali just
updated the chat. It says it appears
that you have to have a DEA license to
get a CS number in New Mexico. So that
is
so it's it's based on a federal uh
regulation
which if I'm like you know it's just
good for me or anyone else to know it's
like okay how do I obtain this? I know
that there's not necessarily a
flowchart. I'm all about the flowchart.
I want to know what I need to do in
order to get the thing that I'm trying
to get. And if there's not a flowchart,
I I get lost. So I get frustrated. I get
angry.
>> Brenda,
>> just to be clear, so it looks like we
you have to have both in order to
um prescribe uh psilocybin.
Well, from a regulatory standpoint, it's
just the controlled substance number.
Uh, as Denali is stating in the chat
that you have to have a DEA license to
be able to get that. Um, and again, we
have reached out as far as to the board
of pharmacy about that. But I really
want to reiterate at this point that,
you know, we did bring these concerns
back to the secretary. We did go over th
those aspects um and the concerns, but
we the department at least is going to
move forward from a regulatory
standpoint with that as a requirement.
>> Thank you.
>> Not to fogg a dead not to fogg a dead
horse, which I may be doing here, but um
if I understand what you're writing
there, that's not for a controlled
substance. It's for a PMP account. A PMP
account is simply so that you can you
can look up prescriptions for controlled
substances on on an account. So I don't
think what you posted there answers the
question. I don't know the answer to the
question, but I don't think that the PMP
is not equivalent to a CS.
>> So sorry to jump everyone. That is
correct, Larry. I'm in the the board
ofies rules right now trying to drill
down on this specific uh piece for you
for you all.
and Ian.
>> So I as I am also now trying to drill
down on the board of pharmacy website, I
found what I would need to apply for a
CS number and it does not have a DEA
requirement. And then on the DEA's
website, a state license is required for
a DEA license. So I don't think it would
be a catch 22 and no one has a DEA
license. Um,
so
thank you. That was all I had. I I had
just been researching. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Dr. Truckner.
>> Yeah. Right. Let's I think in a second
we're I'm going to leave the CS license,
DA license. in this state. My
understanding from talking to one
individual who isn't the inspector
person who has barely all authority um
it was you can apply for a CS license in
this state for up to a year but then you
have to get a DEA license. So it in this
state it again I've worked in lots of
states and this is an unusual state. Um
in general at some point to have a CS
license you're going to have to have a
DEA license. getting a DEA license is
just answering some questions and
writing a large check. Um it it's not
that difficult to get. And the second
question, Chris, I I wanted to bring it
back to liability just for a second.
If we're let's take Colorado for
example, and so as you said, they've
gone through thousands and they just
check with their regular doc. So you
want to you want to go on a journey. You
go to your regular doc. They seem to say
sure you're fine. They don't have any
real particular knowledge about
psilocybin. They haven't been trained
about psilocybin. And then they come to
you and you as a facilitator given their
journey then something goes south. Um,
and so the liability if I'm a if I'm a
malpractice lawyer, I'm going to have a
field book because you're going to say
you were certified by a physician who
has no knowledge of psilocybin.
Um, and you know, the lawsuit is going
to win. Um, it really is at least here
the certifying clinician is going to go
through education
specifically about psilocybin.
So there is going to be a protective
layer there. So if something goes south
risk, your liability is facilitated.
Yeah, it's it's there. But I would
believe a lot more is going to land on
me as the certified clinic is
because I have I will have a malpractice
policy and they're going to have to
walk.
Thank you,
>> Chris.
Yeah, that's not I think really how
Colorado works in general.
um as a facilitator or a clinical
practitioner up in Colorado or clinical
facilitator rather um you will do all of
the screening processes and then if
there's any kind of contraindications
then you can consult with the patient's
doctor or consult with somebody that can
help them you know titrate medicines or
um check for safety of certain
contraindications.
It's not a certifying clinician.
Nobody certifies you from that point. If
you work with a patient as a
facilitator,
um that is the liability remains with
you. It's ultimately up to you to
determine the appropriateness
um
of the patient. And you're trained to do
that.
Okay. Any additional comments?
Right. That's all I have. I'll turn it
back over to you, Ian.
All righty. Well, um, so is there any
more discussion between the board? Does
anyone have anything else that they
would like to say? Are there any
objections to moving forward on a vote
on the CS number requirement?
Chris?
>> Yeah. I just want to say I don't think
that
this any of the new regulations increase
access.
I I still see this as a major
bottleneck. I don't see this as I also
see this as
um
shifting liability where
uh to a larger circle of people where it
needs to remain in the room with the the
patient.
And I think this ultimately just sets up
signature mills that actually do not
um
do not provide any extra layer of safety
at all. Thank you,
Desba.
Um, okay. So, again, kind of for
clarification, what it sounds like is
that
what we're actually voting on is where
we place the CS1 requirement, where
we're actually placing that language,
what in what part of the process that
we're actually placing it, because
um there it ha it just has to be. And
what it sounds like I'm hearing from
Chris is kind of slightly different is
like if we're voting on the CS
requirement,
are we
voting uh it sounds like from what I
hear Chris is saying is that there
shouldn't be a requirement [laughter]
and and that it's and that it's
providing more of a of a of an added
layer to
uh
how this is getting administered. in the
process, right? But what I'm hearing
from uh the department is that we have
that's not what we're voting on. We're
only strictly voting on where in the
process we're actually placing it and
giving it a little bit more room to
breathe and a little more leeway that it
doesn't have to be the starting point.
It could be anywhere kind of sort of
more loosely tied to it. And I just kind
of wanted to make that clarification
because if our hands are tied as far as
like it has to be in the regulations,
then I can understand that we're voting
to like where we're placing it. Um, and
I just wanted to make that clarification
question.
So
currently we're voting to put it kind of
almost on an outside gate um to the
program. Um they basically would check
in ideally with their primary care. If
they are not registered then it would be
um a third party online service um that
would review their medical records and
then go on from that. Um, but just as a
clarification, it's not a CS1. It's just
a controlled substance number cuz like
there's only three people with that CS1
in the state and I don't think Larry has
enough time. [snorts] So, um, but
anyway, Larry,
>> yeah, I mean, this may not affect how
vast, but I do want to clarify something
is that, you know, if it was possible to
um just have prescriptive authority, but
not a controlled substance license,
which is not I don't I'm trying to
figure how many people are in that
category. I know people that work with
all health care systems are required to
have a CS license. I think people often
are for reimbursement. So, I'm I I I
feel a little like maybe we're doing
talking about different things. And I
would actually ask Chris then, too. I
mean, Chris, if it if it said that you
needed to have prescriptive authority,
but you didn't have a controlled
substance license, would that change
your feeling? I I have a feeling it
wouldn't. And so, I'm feel like maybe
we're we're debating the wrong thing.
You know,
>> people understand what I'm saying.
>> Yes, I understand what you're saying.
And I I might need a little more
information about how broad that then
makes makes this my you know my main
concerns are about accessibility and I
don't think
under these regulations this makes it
accessible and increases safety in any
meaningful way. Um, and I I feel like
it's a bottleneck that'll ultimately
um kill this program and just make it
unsustainable at a from a full program
level. I mean, my my wife can't even get
a primary care like and we live in
Albuquerque and it this is this is not
shifting
anything
um from
from, you know, making her be able to
see a physician or a a doctor that's
taken this specialized training that is
willing to accept a large amount of
risk. Um especially because they're
they're
not doing any of the risk mitigation.
They're not writing a prescription and
sending people home. that they are going
to need to. I mean, if I were a um a
license holder and a certifying
clinician, I would only be willing to
sign off on this for
uh people working with care teams that I
was familiar with because they're the
ones that are going to um really make
sure that this is safe and that I'm not
going to get sued for malpractice
because if I just sign a paper and they
go work with somebody,
um I don't know that that's going to go
well and I I think there's a lot of
uncertainty in that whole process
considering this this program is barely
standing up and so how do you even bet
that um but
I mean
how much more broadly will that open up
um
the the pract practitioner pool or the
certified clinician pool.
This is Larry. Um I I don't think it's
going to open it up very much more, but
I'm curious. You I know Denali has
mentioned in the past that she has she
knows a DOM that's in that category, but
I don't think there are very many people
in that category. So I think before we
get too fixated on the CS versus
prescribing facility, it would help to
know that it does sound like we don't
really have a choice actually at this
point in time to be to be honest. Um but
but I think it's important to know. The
other question this is actually for an
if she's still on the call. Um and Mets
um he says usually people are referred
to Colorado psychiatrists. I think
that's probably for things like TRD and
PT PTSD. How hard is that to get people
in Colorado psychiatrists to see people?
How is that playing out in Colorado as
far as the malpractice and liability
concerns? And I don't know if you're on
the call and still open to to commenting
on that
because
has specialized information. And I will
make an exception this once to allow for
public input. Um, and your microphone
has been unmuted.
Sorry about that. It clicked on and off.
Um, my name's Dr. Anne Mets. I'm a
clinical facilitator in Colorado. Um,
and in general, the way that the
workflow happens in Colorado is that
people are referred to individual
providers. Usually, if they have any um
risk factors at all or any
contraindications, they're sent to a
clinical facilitator.
Um, and in the course of screening, if
it warrants um medical clearance or any
sort of approval, um there are a couple
of designated psychiatrists in Colorado.
Herman Escandi is one of them. He is one
of the pratty um facilitators. He has
his own healing center and he you know
typically can do a consultation within
the week. Um so I think you know the way
it's worked and it's worked quite well
um is that there are just people that
are um sort of on call and do it as a
consultation business for for um
different healing centers in the state.
But it's really only in cases where
there are it's not necessarily for
treatment resistant depression or PTSD.
It's when people have pretty significant
medical complications and we wouldn't
want someone um who has an MD to sign
off on whether or not this is
appropriate. Um, I would say that her
mom's opinion, and he might be a great
person to bring into a meeting, um,
really is that if someone's able to walk
up the stairs without any difficulty,
they're usually okay to do psilocybin.
Um, so I think that some of the caution
that we have around the um, contra
indications for psilocybin and also the
medical complications might be a bit
overblown. You know, in practice,
Colorado's had very few medical issues
that have come up. Um, and the screening
process seems to be working quite well.
>> Thank you, Anne. I appreciate people
allowing an to speak. Um,
yeah, I I just want to clarify to what I
said. I I think it is the mental health
concerns and the challenges that I think
are more seriously of a worry than um um
I would agree. I know her mom well
actually. I would agree that um
cardiovascularly if you can walk up
three flights of stairs um you're
probably at low risk although there
would be some exceptions such as the
person who had a heart attack and had
angoplasty or something. So it's there
are specifics. Thank you very much.
>> Chris, sorry.
>> Yeah. And I just want to point out that,
you know, the Colorado program allows
for doctors and psychiatrists to focus
on the patients that really need it
rather than um
trying to bog them down with seeing
every individual patient that and it'll
be unnecessary.
uh get the extra layer of safety where
it's needed and uh let you know let this
be handled at the lowest level possible
otherwise.
>> Perfect. And then Ryan, I mean Kenan,
[snorts]
>> we could we could make a a fun coffee
drinking game for this every time and we
could all be highly caffeinated. Um,
Chris, let me let me ask something if
you don't mind if if what you're
envisioning
the I think the line and volume of
individuals between
people with a controlled substance
license versus people who have are
allowed to prescribe
who have an active prescriptive
authority, which is probably harder to
actually pull than a controlled
substance uh license. like that's a much
harder piece to pin down versus
um
what what I'm hearing from you and I
don't want to put words in your mouth so
tell me if if this is really what you're
getting at. It almost sounds like you
would prefer a system of self-referral
and that's hard. Um and I guess that's
what I'm asking that these people don't
need to have a certifying provider. They
can just show up and request therapy. Is
that is that what you're trying to
is that what you see as the the point
because I think that's
that creates a separate bottleneck about
who can diagnose because you would have
to have these indications and that may
not be all the people that can provide
the service. So I'm just putting that
out there but like to hear your opinion.
No, I I see a system in which people
could show up with a diagnosis to uh a
practitioner, I guess, is the word we're
using here. And then at that point, they
would be medically screened and
psychologically
screened for the program. And any contra
indications then would be required to um
have various levels of consultation
involved to allow the patient to
participate.
And if they don't exist then we you know
the practitioner at that point would be
able to
um
to be able to proceed just based on the
diagnosis at at one point we had the
certifying clinician just
holding diagnostic authority
and that seemed to be broad enough and I
I again don't understand necess
necessarily
who all that opens it up to, but it it
seemed to be broad enough to where the
accessibility issues were not a a
concern at that point. And so,
if we were to move back to diagnostic
authority as being a
um
you know, the person that clears, I
might be more amendable to it. But under
the current regulations, I just don't
see how we can
uh sustain a program. You know, even
even from a
um propagation standpoint,
I don't think there's going to be enough
people for a grower to even be in
business.
So, that's kind of how I'm approaching
this.
>> Yes, if I if I may.
So I think we are probably talking about
similar things just a different word. So
the certifying provider in your mind
does the diagnosis and has no relation
actually to the referral to treatment.
Is that a fair way to say it? And again
I'm trying to better understand. I'm not
trying to say that's what you're what
you're seeing.
>> Yeah. I mean this I think this is going
to be limited to a very few number of
doctors and nurse practitioners who are
willing to accept the risk take the
training
and we're already critically short on
doctors and so I don't
think that the vast majority of people
would have any relationship with these
certifying clinicians at all.
Yeah, and
I appreciate that. I think the question
in my mind is, do we create something
new that's never been done before
or do we look at what we've done that's
the most similar and apply them? And so
I would say a lot of those arguments
you're saying were also things people
brought up about medical marijuana
licenses
previously. I I I remember working in
clinics before it was decriminalized and
we had this pharmacist couldn't write
for it but our physicians that we saw uh
saw these patients would and well there
were some people who chose not to do it
um it was largely for an age cut off
they wouldn't do it for anyone under 25
uh for some neurocognitive development
reasons th this wasn't the issue um and
so
I am a voting designate I am not the
official member on the board. So, I will
stop here, but I would just say that
this has worked in the past and we've
seen it work and provide access. And so,
we can do something completely new and
we take more risk that way. We use the
system we've used in the past. We have
some nothing's perfectly safe, but some
safety in that system.
I would counter that this is not
marijuana and again all the risks
mitigation comes from preparation proper
preparation proper administration
techniques and then integration care
after the administration of the
medicine. You're not sending somebody
home with a prescription of marijuana
which they're performing themselves. the
care team, the practitioner, the
facilitator are going to have a a very
large role in how well the medicine
works. And if we just open this up to
where doctors are signing a paper saying
you're medically cleared, go work with
whoever you want, it's going to open the
door for a lot of risk involved in that
process. And I don't
I don't think doctors are going to be as
willing to accept that risk as they were
with medicinal marijuana
uh where it's just a basically a
prescription and take two of these and
call me in the morning. This is totally
different kind of ball game.
>> Thank you. and
as an agreement with Kenan um
we
someone has to check in and so we're
talking about this like it's a program
ending decision to require controlled
substance licenses and in reality I
think this year there's what 70,000
patients Dominic you can correct me if
I'm wrong um but in the ballpark of that
and So it's able to maintain a patient
population. If we had a similar, you
know, you have to get a renewal every
year, maybe 2 years, then we could
maintain the same amount of physicians
that are maintaining the medical
cannabis program, assuming that there is
a huge crossover in those types of
patients. Oh, 60,000, my mistake. Um,
but
we can definitely support a
market
large enough to sustain the program. I
don't think a controlled substance
requirement is going to be cataclysmic.
Um, thank you. And then Desma,
>> I think I just kind of wanted to get
clarification with because we were
talking about the different risks and
like we're using the same word for
different like categories and I just
wanted to understand from Chris like
what was the risk that is really
concerning because to me in my mind, you
know, identified like the legal the
legal risk, the health risk like heart
problems, etc., climbing through flights
of stairs versus like the actual
medicinal risk. And when you use the
word risk, which one of those three
particularly is like the troubling
aspect of it? Or is there like an even
completely different category of risk
in, you know, it came to me and then it
left? as far as like this idea of the
medical person signing off and then it's
opening up risk like where in that and I
understand like we have a lot of desire
to kind of sort of be patriarchal as and
not that patriarchal but um when you're
being fatherly and and then that's kind
of like the role of the government in
general is like hey we know better than
you as far as like your health and
everything is concerned it's very very
uh patronizing. I can't remember. It's a
patriarchal word, but and I get it. Um,
and I and I totally understand kind of
coming at it from like this own agency,
our own accountability, our own
responsibility,
but then it's just like where do we meet
in that middle ground? Again, it's the
middle ground of these of of patient
responsibility, medical responsibility,
government responsibility, and then also
like, yeah, let's trust the universe to
like take care of us all. And I know
that's where eventually all of us are
probably try when I say all of us, I'm
talking about the psilocybin kind of
environment and those and in meditation
practice type people is that we're
trying to trust that these things will
be okay. And that's where at least I'm
trying to come from, you know, but how
in my agency and I feel like Chris is
doing this and then we're all doing this
to the best of my ability and to what is
is is falling on my consciousness,
right? To be able to be thinking about
the whole universe and the whole world
and all those constituents of the state.
Where in that idea of risk are we
falling in for you that is preventing
this kind of like meeting in the middle
ground?
>> Okay. Um well I'll start with your last
comment there. I don't think we're
meeting in the middle ground anywhere
that we're still requiring access
through uh controlled license number
which is the big hiccup or big access
issue to begin with as far as risk goes
it it's all tied together right so if a
medical
uh the certifying clinician signs off on
a patient he goes and that patient then
goes and works
in a with a
practitioner and facilitator that is
unknown to the certifying clinician.
They don't properly prepare him. The
patient isn't ready for the medicine. He
say freaks out, hurts himself and
others. And next thing you know,
everybody's pointing the finger
everywhere else with liability issues.
Um like who's responsible for this?
I
and then
so now we've we've got malpractice
issues for the certifying clinician and
the practitioner and facilitator.
And um and then we also have an unwell
patient
whereas we shift the liability to where
it belongs in the room with the patient
um right from the start. then
there's nowhere to pass the book. It's
like it belongs here and we can also
weed out where where harm
happens.
>> Okay. Yeah. So it what at least just
from what you said in clarifying
it sounds to me a little contradictory
of the idea that the medicine itself
there is no risk factors. Like in that
statement, it just said that like if the
patient then has an episode, right?
Where they then have the episode of the
low risk, right? First it's saying low
risk, there's no risk to the medicine,
but then now we're saying they had an
episode, so where does the liability
fall? But I hear that it was like we
eliminating the idea of
the risk falling back on the person
falls fully on the person which
I someone else might have a better way
of
perceiving this but
if we're putting it fully on the person
then that then now and then we're
actually doing a disservice of the
program itself.
And that's kind of where I'm falling a
little
uh uncertain of as to like the I'm not
I'm um I'm trying to understand like and
I'm not saying that there isn't an
issue. I totally get it. Um, but if
anyone else can see hear what I'm saying
as far as that kind of flow through of
like where this the liability is
falling, that's kind of the whole point
of why we're making the rules and
regulations because if we're going to
then have the liability on the person
I in in let's just say the real world
that's non-governmental use of medical
psilocybin. That's true, right? I'm
sorry. Like if a friend of mine had a
bad trip, you know, and it was me,
right, that was facilitating this and my
friend or something, yeah, I would feel
really bad about like my friend having a
bad trip, but then I would also kind of
like mitigate this. And I I I don't
know. I guess it's like blameshifting of
my friend to say that they had a bad
trip and that I wasn't involved in it.
But that's just like where if I was like
representing the government then yeah it
would be unfortunately on me that like
you know did I did I did I adhere to all
the protocols? Did I administer the
right amount? Did I have like all of the
procedures and the metrics pointed out
and then signed off on it? And yeah then
yeah I guess that does open me up to my
friend saying hey it was your fault
right and I totally understand that.
But then with this is just like the
person themselves because they accepted
all the risks for for for this for the
use and the trip and the journey.
And I think maybe that is part of part
of the issue is just like wherein does
the government take some of the
responsibility for you know quote
protecting us from ourselves which is uh
another can of worms. Um
yeah I don't So I am not really getting
to a point but I was just trying to kind
of get to a place of clarity of
understanding like what's the hangup
where are the issues that we need to
look at and what is actually our due
diligence and and and duty to
responsibility in having the
conversation making the recommendations
to the department for the rules that are
then going to be you know possibly
affecting andor supporting. Let's hope
like let's maybe using the language of
supporting our our New Mexico residents
and anyone else who is going to be here
and possibly into the future. And I know
we cannot cover everything, but what in
what ways are we actually supporting
that rather than creating barriers maybe
is like the with the idea is that I'm
trying to come at how are we supporting
um accountability? How are we supporting
responsibility? How are we supporting
access
um in the best way possible? And I know
that that's where we're all heading
towards. Um I'm just, you know, I get we
get stuck on the language. Um we get
stuck on the ifs, ands, and thens, and
we're not computers, and thank god we
don't have computers deciding who is
getting this medicine. Please, I'll just
say that. Um okay, that's it.
I would say one of my big hang-ups with
and I think I might be able to clarify
what I'm getting at here is
physical safety is the smallest part of
that and we're we're putting it into the
the gatekeeping function of psilocybin.
So these
certifying clinicians are in charge of
the physical safety of the patient which
uh represents a tiny fraction of the
risk and then puts them at the forefront
of the chain of liability for this
program. when the psychological safety
is far more important and when we
when we start this program out
going through a certifying clinician
who's a doctor um that is
not trained to handle that uh aspect of
it and is certifying them to go work
with a patient or a care team that that
is responsible for that portion. and
that liability can come back on them um
for something they shouldn't be
responsible for and represents a very
small
uh portion of the risk involved in this
whole program. And and I want to just
mention also that yes, okay, cannabis
has grown to where we have 60,000
patients in the in the program, but
cannabis had a huge advantage over this
in that once you got somebody in the
program, they were a daily user. And so
they might be doing an ounce, you know,
using an ounce a week or a month, but
regardless, they keep uh consuming this.
Whereas somebody comes into this, they
might use a half an ounce in a year if
they keep coming back. So from a
propagation standpoint, you don't have
the advantage of having consistent
product moving and uh and again not
being able to sustain that a business um
if we limit the accessibility as much as
I think this will. So, I do think this
kills the program if we continue going
down this road.
>> Thank you. And Brenda,
>> thank you Desba and Chris for all of
these questions um because this
we can only take so much um risk or
think about so much risk and think about
all of these different things. But when
it comes down to training and education,
that's where it it all it all falls.
Because if you have a um staff of people
that are educated, we as a clinician
uh and a therapist, we always take a
risk when we have clients. We never know
we never know how people are going to be
when we're treating them. And so
it it's a um it's worth considering and
not taking assumptions about but be
being prepared for all of these risks.
That's where training and education
comes in because we do our due diligence
in keeping people safe as far as their
mental health goes, their physical
health goes. However,
we do have to start to step into
the the ring of fire here and start to
understand that
this
uh the profession of medical and mental
health is a big risk with all of this.
And yeah, I understand where does the
responsibility lie if something goes
wrong that is um uh for you know that
the legal part of that we never know it
is a it is a infinite amount of
scenarios we can uh come up with and I'm
glad Chris that you're bringing up all
of this stuff because it really helps us
take a really hard look at what is
happening here. However, in the
beginning, we have to take these
precautions. I understand that. And
because of, you know, uh, New Mexico has
these two, the DEA license and the CS
license
that, um, it's overkill maybe in some
places, but it also to speaks to, uh,
uh, keeping everyone safe, including the
patient and the provider. So, this is
where education comes in. And so if we
do our due diligence and being careful
and trying to make sure that everyone
knows that we are getting into territory
that we anything can happen, but we know
that um as a clinician myself,
you know, anyone can be sued in any in
in any part of this chain. So, I get
what you're saying. You know, where does
the the the true liability fall? It
could fall on me. It could fall on the
uh on the uh another caretaker
uh uh or a team member in this in this
um group of people that are taking care
of a um a client. So, um I'm just going
to leave it at that. And you know, I I
really do appreciate your your
questions, Chris, because that's where I
think a lot of this falls. We all take a
risk in the profession that we're in,
and we're doing our best to try to keep
everyone safe as much as possible. Um,
that's all I have to say. Thank you.
>> Thank you. And then Kenan.
Yeah, I I thanks Bren. I think those
that's really high on the on the money.
I would just say that there's no way to
remove the certifying provider
from liability unless they're not
involved in the process. Uh because if
there's a bad experience like we were
talking about in an outcome,
you could say you misdiagnosed them and
they had this bad experience because
they didn't really have PTSD, they had
schizoeffective.
I'm just making it. I'm not saying
that's a legitimate reason, but you
could have these things and then you get
sued um or included in a lawsuit, right?
Um, so if
if that's the goal and that's truly
we're talk we're talking about removing
certified physicians but that means
diagnosis
uh and a lot more assessment goes on the
treating the facility predict which I
actually think might be a bigger
um
rate limiter to access compared to the
model as it exists now uh because the
diagnosis portion is not going to be
able to be done by as many provider
types. Um, and that actually might limit
access in the long run. So I I
no system is perfect and to get to
Despa's thing, it does have the health
care system having some paternalism um
over over individuals. Um, and I get
that and that's an important thing that
we have to weigh. Uh but I think this is
until it's approved by the DEA and then
a lot of places can do it. Uh which will
also
be detrimental to the small grower
market because the for example Medicaid
could then cover it but we will only
cover the synthetic DEA approved
version. Uh, and so
I think this is the best in between, but
I think if we're unable to come to an
answer here, I think we're kind of
I wouldn't say going in a circle, but I
think we need data to answer the
question is what I'm hearing because I
think we're on on opposite sides. Not
opposite sides, we're of differing
opinions and we need data. How many
providers are there? Um, how many, you
know, those are the things that will
help us make a better datadriven
decision. So um I I just throw that out
there. But and the last thing I will say
to you is my anecdotal experience with
healthcare providers is they are more
interested in psilocybin based therapy
than I would say cannabis uh based
therapy. They probably feel it's safer
and has better data and evidence. So the
idea that they'll be less inclined to
prescribe this maybe that's true and
again we would need data uh to answer
that but my personal experience that
more people would be in favor of this
than cannabis which can have more uh
negative side effects by far. Um so I'll
just put that put that out there.
>> Thank you. And I guess a question I have
for
Brenda is let's imagine a scenario where
we took out the doctor requirement.
We're going to then be imposing
contraindications
assessment onto a therapist. Would you
feel comfortable accepting the liability
for ensuring someone does not have
medical contraindications?
>> Um that's a very good question. Um,
if that were the case, um,
if I'm working with a if I'm working
with a patient and I'm doing an
assessment and I ask them, you know,
hey, do you have any, you know, uh, uh,
physical issues?
um and let's say um they do and I have
to use my professional opinion and and
either uh say okay I think how long's it
been since you've seen a doctor number
one
uh two do you have a doctor or uh
someone a nurse practitioner someone who
can do an actual physical exam on you uh
so I'm going to do my due diligence
with that.
Uh, of course, if uh and I have had
clients uh that um
not that they withheld information,
uh they simply forgot. Oh, yeah. I you
know
uh yeah, I had a uh you know uh a thing
a medical thing a while back. Okay. What
was that? you know, but they'll forget
and then maybe along the line they
remember and we're in the middle of this
and it's like, "Oh, hey, sorry, but I
have to deny you." Um, I do it all the
time. I I I think that um if I see any
red flags, I say, "Okay, you need to see
your doctor. You need to see a
psychiatrist before we go any further
with um finding the proper treatment for
you." Um, do I feel comfortable with
that?
Um, personally, yes, because I I trust
that because of my years of training,
that's what I have to fall back on. Um,
if I had a uh physician
uh in the wings, yes, that would make me
feel even um better because right now
it's a gunshot. I have to I have to say
okay what kind of insurance do you have
uh if you have an insurance that has a
list of physicians there I don't think
you know any of those physicians have
had any uh psilocybin training
let's see you know what the process is
so it it will go through all of these
things it's it it has to in order to
provide safety and education too for
that um for the patient because I want
to make sure that the patient is ready
for something like this. It's it for me
it's no different if I have someone that
comes to me, they they have some uh they
know there's something wrong with them
and I have a feeling that they have
bipolar, I'm going to refer them to a
psychiatrist,
uh a list of psychiatrists that they can
go to. In the meantime, I'm still
working with that client until they can
get uh a full assessment on that. So,
that's kind of how it it it it has been
working for me and I think many other cl
uh therapists, especially in the mental
health uh part of it. Now, if it were
something that came to me and they said
they had a diagnosis that they were
going to only live for 6 months,
now I would have I would say, you know,
go through all of the questions and say,
"Hey, would you like to have end of life
care?" And and they want to go through
the psilocy psilocybin program. I would
have to go to the list of uh people that
are providing that. So I I think to
answer your question, do I feel
comfortable about um whether or not
having a physician uh on the team? Yes,
I would feel more comfortable. Where
does the liability land? We don't know.
That's where the risk lies. So it it's
just like anything else. If I if I am
diagnosing somebody with ADHD and they
need to have a full assessment and they
want to um get a prescription for that,
that's
that's the the right protocol to go by.
So, I hope I answered your question you
with this.
>> Yes, thank you. Um I am going to get to
Desbon and Dan. Um I'm just going to ask
that you guys keep it a little bit
short. We are running out of time and we
still have to get to public comment.
>> Uh thank you and sorry I will try to be
quick. So I just want to say you that
was a good question Brenda. Thank you
for answering and just kind of I know
it's not the same as psilocybin but as a
massage therapist um whenever someone
comes in to me and I you know we have
the little mini questionnaire. It's not
a diagnostic tool but we do ask you know
do you have any contra
contraindications? Are there any
medications that I should be aware of?
Sometimes I'm very specific if it's like
heart or blood thinners depending on
their age and their presenting um or in
any injuries that I should be aware of
prior for them getting onto my table,
right? So that's my due diligence and my
responsibility. But that's like the
second layer after they have you know
fill out their health questionnaire and
you know double-checking with them
because sometimes people don't you know
they forget. Um then as they're on their
table I assess the body. I decide you
know hey this doesn't look very good. I
ask them questions. There's that third
layer. You know, I've done my
responsibility. And based on
responsibility, I just wanted to read
this really quickly. This is one of my
favorite quotes, and it's from Admiral
Rickover. Responsibility is a unique
concept. You may share it with others,
but your portion is not diminished. You
may dis delegate it, but it is still
with you. If responsibility is
rightfully yours, no evasion or
ignorance or passing the blame can shift
the burden to someone else. Unless you
can point your finger at the man who is
responsible when something goes wrong,
then you have never had anyone really
responsible. So again the aim for all of
us here is to be as responsible to the
best of our ability and our capacity and
we are human and this is you know the
regulatory process isn't always it's
fallible there are some problems but you
know with our our our full consciousness
you know I'm definitely hoping that
that's why I'm extending the
conversation and asking the questions of
Chris like where in this are we like you
know that the process of conversation
will eventually get us to like an
understanding of of each other. So
that's it.
>> And Dan,
>> thanks Ian. Um, real quick on your
patient uh committee, patient safety
committee, did y'all come up with like
tiers of types of contraindications for
the treatment.
>> Um, so
>> I thought you had has some discussion on
that. So I'm curious as like I know that
if there are tiers of like as a patient
comes in and says we I don't have any of
these things that's a very low-risk
patient that may be able to be referred
directly into into a facilitator. But if
there were tiers of patients that had
other contra indications, could that not
be the trigger that moves them into
needing this this clinician role? Just
curious. Put it out there. I know we
don't have time to get into it, but I
just wanted to ask.
I think that would violate um equal
treatment under the law. If you are
treating the people that are healthier
and in a more expedited fashion, um that
would end up becoming an equal treatment
issue. But we do need to set the next
meeting date and then we can set turn on
to public comment. I'm going to let
everyone hear from the public. Oh,
sorry, Dominic.
>> Yeah. Um, Ian, I just wanted to before
uh it moves on to the public comment, I
just wanted to thank everybody. I
appreciate all of the conversation. I
appreciate the different viewpoints. I
think it's very important. Uh, you know,
and I think what it really comes down to
is it really does show that we are
trying to create the best program
possible. And while we may not always
have the same viewpoints, you know, the
passion, the the concern is definitely
evident and we really do hear it. Um, I
do want to let everybody know that
because of some of the timing issues in
order from um, uh, you know, to be able
to meet the goal of having the first
patients in December, we are going to
move forward with a regulation hearing
and we are looking at the end of August.
Now, of course, we still have some of
the training and so some of those
aspects that are being developed and
considered and so we still do have those
portions and I'm looking forward to that
especially this afternoon um to see some
of that. Um, but I did want to make sure
that everybody knew we are moving
forward from the department standpoint
with setting that regulatory hearing.
Um, because again, we just need to make
sure that we also provide enough time
for people to be able to get training
and to be able to register in the
program and move uh for all of that. So,
I just want to make sure and let you
know that that part is happening is
going to be moving forward. So, thank
you.
Alrighty. Um,
so let's go ahead and set the next date.
When does
meeting next sound good for all of you?
I know Dominic, you're out the week of
the 27th.
29th.
>> Uh, it's the week of the 27th. That's
correct. Uh, and mostly out or traveling
through that. Um, as I mentioned in one
of the other meetings, uh, Dr. Trucker
and I were invited by SAMA to a
conference looking at data gaps with
regard to psilocybin. Um and uh so we'll
actually be traveling to DC and back uh
and the conference of course that week.
So um uh so we won't be available the
department or at least I will not be
available during that week. Um but the
if you're looking as far as for
potential Fridays um the following
Friday um on the 14th the end of life
care actually did take the morning slot
already on that and has scheduled for
that but the afternoon is open on that
day on the 14th if you were looking for
similar pattern. Um if not there's also
the 21st.
>> Does the 100 p.m. and the 14th work for
everyone?
Seeing thumbs up. All righty. Um if
there are no objections, so we will meet
on the
14th out one.
All righty. And then I will turn over to
the department to call for public
comment.
>> This is Larry. Can I have one other
comment here?
>> Yes. So sorry. Is there anyone that's on
the call that has the ability to to sort
out the answer to the question of how
many people are there that have
procriptive authority without controlled
substance license? I realize it doesn't
actually affect the immediate um
decision, but it does seem an important
thing to know in the future. I'm not
sure if that's something that um Keenan
I don't know if you have access to that
information but because we do have
people advocating for prescriptive
authority as the bar and so I would help
to know if that would change things
much.
Yeah, I'll just put out this is probably
a discussion for RLD
um regulatory licensing division which
covers all boards except medical which
should have a controlled substance and
nursing and I think there's some
variation within that but all almost all
other I shouldn't say all but a lot of
the other health professions will be
regulated through that and they could
tell you who has prescriptive authority
and to what scope right like emergency
medical technicians have some
prescriptive authority but it's very
different than just broad scope
prescribing practices. It's very
structured. So, um probably a discussion
with Dr. Cole Pepper with the regulatory
licensing department.
>> Okay. Uh thank you, Kenan. Thank you,
Larry. Um shall we move to public
comment?
>> Yes.
Okay. Uh for individuals who are
interested in providing public comment,
you can just go ahead and raise your
hand. The information on how to do that
is in the meeting chat and then we will
call on individuals in order.
>> All right. And we have uh three minutes
per comment. And because we're low on
time, I will give a time check when
there are 30 seconds remaining in your
time. Uh but we'll begin with Greg. Your
mic has been enabled.
>> This is a question for Hi. Thank you
everyone. This is uh been a wonderful
debate and uh complicated issue.
New subject
question for the department. Will the
program's outcome data and cultivation
compliance software be openly bid for
this program or has a vendor already
been selected?
So, uh this is actually public comment.
Um it's not actually uh question time
but just to answer as far as for um the
research purposes as collecting data um
that has not been determined at this
point. As far as for creating the
patient registry aspects uh we are
continuing to move forward with our
current vendor that we have for other
program.
>> All right. and Kate Hawk, your mic's
been enabled.
>> Yeah, I'll try to make this one minute.
Thanks everybody for wrestling with all
of this. Um, you know, we've heard the
parallels with medical cannabis and just
haven't really heard um discussion
involving medical ketamine. I've worked
with ketamine assisted therapy for quite
a few years and really it's um you know
as far as the path went people found or
wanted to do ketamine assisted therapy
usually not hearing about it through
their doctor but finding a practitioner
like me. I worked closely with a doctor
who could prescribe and of course it was
ketamine so it had to be a regular
prescription. So I think that in the
team uh the concept of teams people will
you know have relationships between
providers and medical people and so
there will be multiple entry points as
long as the the system is clear and
covers everything that's needed. So I
just for better or for worse it would be
worthwhile to look at what's being done
with ketamine. Thank you.
>> Thank you Kate
Denali. your mic is enabled.
>> Hi, good morning everyone. Um, two
really quick things I think that came
up. when there was this question of
whether the encounter with a certifying
um clinician could be build and I
understand um that as it's currently
um as [clears throat] it's currently
operating under the medical cannabis
program
um that that is a billable encounter. Um
I'm I'm a little bit worried um about
the way that the regulation reads
specifically because it's requesting
that the provider evaluate it's
essentially designing the encounter
specifically for the entry into the
medical psilocybin program. So, if I
were the federal government overseeing
our Medicaid system or if I were um if I
were um coverage council for a private
payer, I would look at the regulation
and say, "Actually, this encounter only
happened for the prescription of a
schedule one substance and deny the
claim or claw it back if it had already
been made and was came up in an audit."
So I I think um similarly you know there
was a lot of conversation about
liability and I agree with the consensus
of the board you know that there's only
so much we can do to limit that but I do
think that the requirement to provide um
you know a risk and benefit analysis
does increase the the liability from the
provider and I just made a note that um
that um me member Ryan from HCA They um
mentioned that the um you know that
really it's the medical it's the the med
it's an assessment of medical risk that
we want. We've gone beyond that by
requiring that there be a risk and
benefit analysis. I think that if it
were revised to just require um an
assessment of medical risk, one that's
going to create less risk of clawbacks
and to you know less other professional
liability on the certifying clinician.
Um and then I just want to say I I think
I um have been primarily, you know, the
proponent that we the we maybe um look
at prescriptive authority instead of the
controlled substance number. And I
recognize that this may be my own
provider bias. So, so it's my primary
care provider um that I've had for a
long time and trust and rely on
>> for medication management um you know
doesn't have the CS number. I appreciate
the recommendation that we maybe go to
RLD and I'm I'm happy to take that on if
I can get a connection to um Dr. Cold
Pepper.
Thank you, Denali. Uh, and Amy, your mic
is enabled.
>> Amy, if you're speaking, we cannot hear
you.
>> Hi. Can you hear me now?
>> Yes. Okay, great. Thank you. Um, I want
to thank the psilocybin advisory board
for the careful deliberation they're uh
doing today and here the the really kind
of catch that you're in that you have to
have this qualifying
um uh disqualifying person in there or
language in there as well as the the
concerns about bottlenecks. Um, one
thing that I will say is that I I agree
with Brenda that the training and
education really needs to be the point
at which facilitators develop that
ongoing ethical practice that is uh
really needs to be something that's
tracked and and people can't be trained
really just in one weekend to
facilitate. They really need an ongoing
kind of um layering process of that
ethical consideration because it's it's
ongoing. is non-stop and it requires an
enhanced level of ethical practice and
informed consent all the way through so
that the client themselves or this
jourer themselves also develops that
framework and compass inside themselves.
Right? So that it's not necessarily the
facilitator saying yes or no. It's also
the client being informed enough that
they're going I'm double thinking this.
I'm thinking about whether to proceed
given my medical or my complexity in my
comorbid um diagnosis if they have
complex trauma or something like that
and they don't have stable system around
them. So I just wanted to say that I
teach a 96-hour program at Southwestern
and that is it's like people usually
finish all those classes within two
years, two and a half years. Now, we
could do that sooner for a facilitator
training program, but I still think that
people need to have an ongoing kind of
layering process because ethics is not
just learned in one weekend
or practice in one weekend. It's a
continual coming back. And so, an
ongoing facilitator practicum that might
be periodically need to happen um would
be also something that I would recommend
for the education training. I can't be
at the afternoon meeting. Sorry, Brenda.
hopefully make a future one. Sorry.
Thank you.
>> Okay. Is there are there any other
individuals who wanted to provide
comment?
If not, back to you, Ian.
>> Alrighty. Well, on behalf of the board,
we thank everyone for who showed up
today to listen to participate. All of
the board members who are here, thank
you guys so much for taking time out of
your day um to be here with us. I know
all of you have very important jobs. So,
just thank you again to the Department
of Health. Thank you for hosting this um
video call, for sending out the invite
links, for being our point of contact
for legal issues, for that kind of
thing. So, we really appreciate all of
the work that goes on behind the scenes.
And to all of the general population who
have just been supporting this program
from the bottom of my heart, we thank
you. Um, and have a wonderful rest of
your weekend.
>> And on behalf of the department, to
everyone and to the board members, thank
you as well and look forward to seeing
those who will be in the meeting this
afternoon. And uh, have a great weekend
as well if we don't see you there.